MILAN KACAR

Software & Survey Engineer

https://milankacar.github.io/CV/nilan-kacar



ABOUT ME

Milan Kacar

I am a Software Engineer & Survey Engineer with 2 years of professional experience. I graduated Geodesy at Graz University of Technology in Austria, where I work as a project and teaching assistant. I am currently enrolled in two Master's degree programs: Geodesy & Computer Science at the same university. I grew up in Mrkonjic Grad (Republic of Srpska, BA) where I finished my high school having Mathematics, Logic and Physics at higher level.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Date of birth

O1.09.1995

Birthplace

Citizenship

Marital status

Single

Sex

Male

EDUCATION

GYMNASIUM

BSc Geomatics Engineering University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Geodesy University of Technology, TU Graz

Master's Degree Programme - Computer Science University of Technology, TU Graz

🛗 2020-Present 👂 Graz, Austria

UNIVERSITY & PERSONAL PROJECTS

- STOCK PRICES PREDICTOR Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect prices fluctuation for stocks considering different indexes (SP 500, Dow Jones, DAX etc.)
- RUSHB APP Mobile application for calling a waiter and ordering food in bars and restaurants. http://www.dolcevita.rushb.app/client.php
- SCIENTIFIC PAPER MINER This project is GOOGLE for scientific papers.
- POLLEN TREE DETECTOR (FROM SATELLITE IMAGES) This project presents an automated tree detecting and identification method based on image processing of satellite imagery.
- DIFFERENT SIGNAL PROCESSING PROJECTS Mostly projects on GNSS signals.
- GRAVITY ANOMALY MAPS GRACE misson.
- KALMAN FILTER · ADEVANCED KALMAN FILTER · PARTICLE FILTER as a part of indoor navigation.
- DIFFERENT ARDUINO PROJECTS Mostly projects from youtube tutorials and combination of different projects.

LOOKING FOR

"To work in a progressive and dynamic organization where one could solve scientific enigmas and contribute towards welfare of society"

TECHNICAL STRENGTH

Python	•••••
C/C++	••••
GIS	•••••
PostgreSQL	••••
Navigation	••••
MATLAB	•••••
GNSS	••••
Signal Processing	•••••
Java	••••
Data Structures & Algorithms	••••
MySQL	••••
Docker	••••
PHP	••••
Linux	••••
R	••••
Apache Spark	••••
Skala	••••
Java Script	••••

DISSERTATION WORK

BSc Thesis

Database for cycling routes

- Entity Relationship Diagram.
- Building the Database.
- Conversion from analog to digital maps.

MSc Thesis

PV (Photovoltaic) panels detection from satellite images

- Project uses AI (Artificial intelligence) and ML (Machine learning) as a hybrid approach to detect panels.
- Building an independent model to work on different datasets.
- Cloud computing
- YOLOv5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant

TU Graz

March 2021 - Present

Q Graz. Austria

- Integrated navigation
- Sensor fusion
- Indoor navigation

Software Engineer

TU Graz

Esp 2019 - Present

Q Graz, Austria

- Automation
- Statistics
- Geoinformatics
- Automotive industry

Survey Engineer GEODATA

Semmering Basistunnel, Austria

- Tunnel surveying
- 3D Laser scanner measurements

HOBBIES



Reading

I am trying to read a book per week.



Sports Addict

At a young age I enjoyed playing tennis, but my interests migrated towards Fitness and healthy food.



Travelling

After living in a rustic, small town for the past 18 years, I was craving change and adventure. Six years later, I've traveled to more places during college than the first two decades of my life.

STRENGTHS

Hard-working Decision Making

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Motivator & Leader

Conflict Resolution

Time Management

Target oriented Able to travel

Flexibility and Adaptability

Problem solver

LANGUAGES

Serbian | Croatian | Bosnian German English Russian

